om4.com.au 2019-03-19

# Privacy Policy | OM4

This Privacy Policy is effective from 25 May 2018.

Your privacy is critically important to us. At OM4, we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our services.
  * We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.

Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates and clarifies these principles.

### Who We Are and What This Policy Covers

OM4 is a company based in Western Australia, Australia.

This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use:

  * Our websites (including om4.com.au, wczap.com and my.om4.com.au);
  * Our WooCommerce Extensions that are available for purchase via the WooCommerce.com Extension Store.
  * Our WordPress plugins that are available via the wordpress.org plugins directory.
  * Our design, development and consulting services.
  * Other software written by us.
  * Other services defined as Services in the [OM4 Terms of Service](http://om4.com.au/terms-of-service/).

Throughout this Privacy Policy we’ll refer to the above collectively as “Services.”

Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

### Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better. We collect information in three ways: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our Services, and from outside sources. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

#### _Information You Provide to Us_

It’s probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  * **Basic Information:**  We ask for basic information from you (such as name, email address, address, phone number) in order to provide our Services to you.
  * **Transaction and Billing Information:**  If you pay for a Service from us–you will provide additional payment information that is required to process the transaction and your payment, such as your name, credit card information, and contact information.
  * **Content Information:**  Depending on the Services you use, you may also provide us with information about you in draft and published content (such as for your website). For example, if you write a blog post that includes biographic information about you, we will have that information, and so will anyone with access to the Internet if you choose to publish the post publicly. This might be obvious to you…but it’s not to everyone!
  * **Credentials:**  Depending on the Services you use, you may provide us with credentials for your website or associated accounts (like your WordPress username and password, Google Account username or password). For example, WooCommerce Extension users may provide us with these credentials in order for us to troubleshoot issues on your website more quickly.
  * **Communications With Us (Hi There!):**  You may also provide us information when you communicate with our staff via our Service Desk, email or phone communication channels.

#### _Information We Collect Automatically_

We also collect some information automatically:

  * **Log Information:**  Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information. We collect log information when you use our Services..
  * **Usage Information:**  We collect information about your usage of our Services. For example, we may collect information about the actions that site administrators and users perform on your OM4 built website–in other words, who did what, when and to what thing on a site. We use this information to, for example, provide our Services to you, as well as get insights on how people use our Services, so we can make our Services better.
  * **Location Information:**  We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Services from certain geographic regions.
  * **Information from Cookies & Other Technologies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. OM4 uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our Services, as well as track and understand email campaign effectiveness and to deliver targeted ads.

#### _Information We Collect from Other Sources_

We may also get information about you from other sources. For example, if you submit a support request via the WooCommerce.com Extension Store, we will receive information from that service (such as your name, email address, extension purchase history in order to provide support to you.

### How And Why We Use Information

#### _Purposes for Using Information_

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * To provide our Services;
  * To further develop and improve our Services–for example by adding new features that we think our users will enjoy or will help them to create and manage their websites more efficiently;
  * To monitor and analyse trends and better understand how users interact with our Services, which helps us improve our Services and make them easier to use;
  * To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition–for example, we may analyse how many individuals purchased a Service after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our Services after a certain length of time;
  * To monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, protect the security of our Services, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities, fight spam, and protect the rights and property of OM4 and others, which may result in us declining a transaction or the use of our Services;
  * To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by OM4 and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on OM4 and our products;

#### _Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information_

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that: (1) The use is necessary in order to fulfil our commitments to you under our [Terms of Service](http://om4.com.au/terms-of-service/) or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable access to our website on your device or charge you for a paid plan; or (2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or (3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or (4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalise your experience; or (5) You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyse them later on.

### Sharing Information

#### _How We Share Information_

We do not sell our users’ private personal information. We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * **Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:**  We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  * **Third Party Vendors:**  We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us, or to provide their services to you or your site. This group includes vendors that help us provide our Services to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information, fraud prevention services that allow us to analyse fraudulent payment transactions, postal and email delivery services that help us stay in touch with you, customer chat and email support services that help us communicate with you, registrars, registries, and data escrow services that allow us to provide domain registration services, and your website hosting provider), those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns), those that help us understand and enhance our Services (like analytics providers), and companies that make products available on our websites (such as the extensions on WooCommerce.com), who may need information about you in order to, for example, provide technical or other support services to you. We require vendors to agree to privacy commitments in order to share information with them.
  * **Legal Requests:**  We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.
  * **To Protect Rights, Property, and Others:**  We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of OM4, third parties, or the public at large. For example, if we have a good faith belief that there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury, we may disclose information related to the emergency without delay.
  * **Business Transfers:**  In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that OM4 goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * **With Your Consent:**  We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction. For example, we may share your information with third parties with which you authorise us to do so, such as social media services.
  * **Aggregated or De-Identified Information:**  We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Services.
  * **Published Support Requests:**  And if you send us a request (for example, via a support email or one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish that request in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

#### _Information Shared Publicly_

Information that you choose to make public is–you guessed it–disclosed publicly. That means, of course, that information like your public profile, posts, other content that you make public on your website, and your comments on other websites, are all available to others–and we hope you get a lot of views! Public information may also be indexed by search engines or used by third parties. Please keep all of this in mind when deciding what you would like to share.

### How Long We Keep Information

We retain Personal Information we collect from you where we have a legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a Service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).

### Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorised access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks and using HTTPS encryption.

### Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  * **Limit the Information that You Provide:**  You can choose not to provide us with optional account information, profile information, and transaction and billing information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide this information, certain features of our Services may not be accessible.
  * **Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:**  You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
  * **Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:**  At this time, OM4 does not respond to “do not track” signals across all of our Services. However, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using OM4’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of OM4’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * **Close Your Account:**  While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Services, you can request cancellation of those services. Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after cancellation, as described in How Long We Keep Information above–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

### Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can do this by contacting us. EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

### Controllers and Responsible Companies

Holipac Pty Ltd t/as OM4 are based at 9/316 Onslow Roadd, Shenton Park, Western Australia, 6008 Australia.

### How to Reach Us

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please [contact us](http://om4.com.au/contact/).

### Other Things You Should Know (Keep Reading!)

#### _Analytics Services Provided by Others_

Other parties may provide analytics services via our Services. These analytics providers may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our Services and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognise your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyse and track usage and determine the popularity of certain content. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by OM4 and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

#### _Third Party Software_

If you’d like to use third party plugins, WooCommerce extensions that enable services provided by third parties, or other third party software, please keep in mind that when you interact with them you may provide information about yourself (or your site visitors) to those third parties. We don’t own or control these third parties and they have their own rules about collection, use and sharing of information, which you should review.

#### _Visitors to Our Clients’ Websites_

We also process information about visitors to our clients’ websites, on behalf of our clients and in accordance with our client agreements. Please note that our processing of that information on behalf of our clients for their websites isn’t covered by this Privacy Policy. We encourage our clients to post a privacy policy that accurately describes their practices on data collection, use, and sharing of personal information.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, OM4 may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. OM4 encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy.  Your further use of the Services after a change to our Privacy Policy will be subject to the updated policy.

Thank you [Automattic](http://automattic.com/privacy) for generously sharing your Privacy Policy wording.
